An odyssey, in which the smallest gestures become epic and
when the body is the last resource for protest.
Hunger is a drama, history film directed by Steve McQueen.
The story of Bobby Sands, the IRA member who led the 1981 hunger strike during The
Troubles in which Irish Republican prisoners tried to win political status.
Bobby Sands, played by Michael Fassbender.
Ray Lohan, played by Stuart Graham.
Priest, played by Liam Cunningham.
Raymond's Mother, played by Helena Bereen.
Raymond's Wife, played by Laine Megaw.
Davey Gillen, played by Brian Milligan.
Hunger is a 2008 historical drama film about the 1981 Irish hunger strike.
It was directed by Steve McQueen (in his feature directorial debut) and
starred Michael Fassbender, Liam Cunningham, and Liam McMahon.
It premiered at the 2008 Cannes Film Festival, winning the
prestigious Caméra d'Or award for first-time filmmakers.
It went on to win the Sydney Film Prize at the Sydney Film Festival, the Grand Prix of the Belgian Syndicate of Cinema Critics,
best picture from the Evening Standard British Film Awards, and received two BAFTA nominations, winning one.
The film was also nominated for eight awards at the
2009 IFTAs, winning six at the event.
The film stars Fassbender as Bobby Sands, the Provisional Irish Republican Army (IRA) member who led the second IRA hunger strike and participated in the no wash protest (led
by Brendan "The Dark" Hughes) in which Irish republican prisoners tried to regain political status after it had been revoked by the British government in 1976.
It outlines events in the Maze Prison in the period leading
up to the hunger strike and its aftermath.
The film explores themes of prison, police brutality,
prisoner, hunger strike, biography.
The tone is dark and emotional.